x2vol.com 2016-03-14

# x2VOL - Privacy Policy

**Effective 01/01/2015**

x2VOL, owned and operated by intelliVOL, is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Privacy Policy applies to the x2VOL web site [www.x2VOL.com](https://www.x2vol.com/), and our x2VOL mobile application (for [iPhone/iPad](https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/myx2vol/id897794733?mt=8) and [Android](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.quicsolv.x2vol)) and governs data collection and usage. By using the x2VOL web site and mobile application, you consent to the data practices described in this policy.

x2VOL has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](https://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only the information that may be collected through this web site, [www.x2VOL.com](https://www.x2vol.com/), and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [webmaster@intellivol.com](mailto:webmaster@intellivol.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

**Collection of Personal Information**

x2VOL collects personal information, such as e-mail address, a parent's e-mail address, name, home or work address, telephone number, and mobile number. x2VOL also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, school you attend, interests and favorites.

**Log Files**

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and stoore it in log files. This information may include protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you to improve marketing analytics, or site functionality. You may also provide personal information about other people, such as their email address. This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided. 

x2VOL encourages you to review the privacy policy of web sites you choose to link to from x2VOL so that you can understand how those web site collect, use and share your information. x2VOL is not responsible for the privacy policy or other content on web site outside of the x2VOL and x2VOL family of web sites.

For organizations, we provide a way to add additional people to your organizations profile, and we will collect name, e-mail address and phone numbers of additional members you wish to add to your profile. We use this information to initiate messages from the system to organization contacts, identify contact and project locations, and facilitate contact between organization managers. Organizations may including both volunteering organizations, which provide opportunities, and sponsoring organizations (such as schools) that monitor, track, and report on the activities of volunteers.

Organizations may manage projects, including adding new projects, reviewing existing ones, and deleting projects. Projects may be defined as unstructured projects or with defined event calendars requiring signup. To enable this functionality, organizations will be able to view basic information such as the names of volunteers signing up for its projects and events and the hours they claim for events, and will have the option of initiating contact with those volunteers through the system. As subscribers, organizations and their designated contacts are able to receive detailed project tracking and progress reporting and define approved projects and organizations which are given preference in searches by that organization's volunteers.

Sponsoring organizations may define groups of volunteers with independent sets of goals to be applied to volunteers within those groups and are able to see basic information such as name, student identifier, and e-mail address in order to verify that the volunteer's membership is appropriate.

For volunteers, we provide the ability to search for and review volunteering opportunities based on your profile information and volunteering preferences. Volunteers may claim time spent on structured projects defined by organizations or on personal unstructured projects. Hours claimed for structured projects can be verified by organizations and approved by schools or sponsoring organizations to provide auditability. You will also be able to view logged and approved volunteer hours, on-going projects and upcoming events, groups the volunteer is a member of, goals and goal deadlines, and progress toward those goals. You may also keep track of your volunteer days in a customized event calendar.

**Mobile**

When using our mobile application the only information we will ask for is the contact details of a third party to verify your time spent on that job. We will collect the name, phone number and email address so that they may be contacted.

You are able to add activities and view all activities and recurring activities. You may also edit or delete activities as well. We will send you alerts within the application of upcoming events as a reminder.

We do not ask you for, access or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or services.

**Profiles**

Once you have created an account you are able to create a profile. We will ask for certain information such as company name, company URL, company's mission statement, etc. This information is viewable by the organizations that you are volunteering for only and will not be displayed to any other users of the site.

**Use of Personal Information**

x2VOL collects and uses personal information to operate the x2VOL web site and deliver the services you have requested such as allowing you to track volunteer work hours, manage projects, view your dashboard, view groups and goals, sign up for new volunteer work, track progress toward goals and keep track of recent activities. x2VOL also uses your personal information to inform you of other products or services available from x2VOL and its affiliates. x2VOL may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. Mobile phone numbers are collected for future use specifically for texting event reminders to registered users. If you want to be removed from this future feature e-mail [webmaster@intellivol.com](mailto:webmaster@intellivol.com) from the registered e-mail address with the mobile number that should be removed.

x2VOL does not sell, share, rent or trade personal information with third parties other than as disclosed within this privacy policy.

x2VOL may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personal information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party.

In addition, x2VOL may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you e-mail or postal mail, provide customer support, process payments or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to x2VOL, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

x2VOL does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

x2VOL keeps track of the web site and pages our customers visit within x2VOL, in order to determine what x2VOL services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within x2VOL to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

x2VOL web site will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on x2VOL or the site, comply with a judicial proceeding or court order; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of x2VOL; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of x2VOL, or the public.

In the event IntelliVOL goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via e-mail and/or prominent notice on our web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

**Choice**

We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personal information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a service from us but do not wish to receive any additional promotional material from us or on behalf of our affiliates, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication or by e-mailing us at [webmaster@intellivol.com](mailto:webmaster@intellivol.com).

**Tracking Technologies**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by intelliVOL and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers [specify type e.g. online customer support provide, etc]. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' moments around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We use cookies for purchasing, to remember users' settings, and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the indivvidual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

**Local Storage Objects (Flash)**

Third parties with whom we artner to provide certain features on out site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as Flash to collect and store information. To manage Flash LSOs plese click here: www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html. 

**Surveys**

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys or contests on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personal information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name, e-mail address, parents e-mail address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to notify you when the survey has been posted to the site and to monitor the site traffic or personalize the site.

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satsfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [webmaster@intellivol.com](mailto:webmaster@intellivol.com).

**Social Media Widgets**

Our web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Security of your Personal Information**

x2VOL secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. x2VOL secures the personal information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When sensitive information (such as a credit card number) or personal information (such as name, phone number, and e-mail address) or is transmitted to other web site, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Access to Personal Information**

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, or delete inaccuracies by making the change within the "your profile" section of the site or by contacting us at [webmaster@intellivol.com](mailto:webmaster@intellivol.com). We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [webmaster@intellivol.com](mailto:webmaster@intellivol.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Changes to this Policy**

x2VOL may change this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by e-mail (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact Information**

x2VOL welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you believe that x2VOL has not adhered to this Policy, please contact x2VOL at [webmaster@intellivol.com](mailto:webmaster@intellivol.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.

**x2VOL**  
P.O. Box 613  
Coppell, TX 75019  
(866) 906-6400
